ncregister.com 2019-03-03

# National Catholic Register Privacy Policy

This web site is owned and operated by EWTN News, Inc., a public charity based in the United States that supports the Eternal Word Television Network (EWTN). 

We recognize that visitors to our site may be concerned about the information they provide to us, and how we treat that information. This Privacy Policy addresses those concerns and our commitment to protecting your privacy on this web site. The information we collect from you is used to improve the content of our web site and to provide you with information, products or other services available to you through EWTN News. This Privacy Policy may be changed or updated from time to time and we recommend that you review these terms periodically.

**Our Policy**

EWTN News respects and protects the privacy of our online visitors and donors. EWTN News does not disclose, give, sell or transfer to third parties any personal information about our visitors without their permission, unless required by law.

Throughout its history, EWTN News has never shared its donor mailing lists or personal information with third parties. It remains EWTN News's policy that mailing lists, both postal and electronic, are never sold or exchanged with third parties.

EWTN News is part of the EWTN family.  EWTN, EWTN Religious Catalogue, and EWTN News are related public charities that work together. Because EWTN News is a supporting organization of EWTN, EWTN is not a third party to this policy and we may share information between the public charities. 

**Some Information is Necessary to Complete a Donation or Fulfill an Order**

If you place an order with EWTN News, some of your personal information is required for us to process your payment, and ship the order to you.  We collect your name, address(es), phone number, email address, and payment information.  This information is used to fulfill your order and communicate with you about your order or donation.  EWTN News may telephone, send postal mail, or email you about the order and transaction. 

In order to detect fraud or security issues, the information you provide, and other information such as information automatically collected from website visitors may be analyzed by the devices we use in our infrastructure to detect fraud or security issues.

**Credit Card and Other Personal Information**

EWTN News uses industry standard efforts such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers (SSL) to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information. We make every reasonable effort to prevent the loss, misuse or theft of the information under our control. 

We care about the safety and security of online transactions. We use the industry standard high grade encryption and security protocol to communicate with your browser software. This method makes it extremely difficult for anyone else to intercept the credit card information you send to us.

When handling your payment information, EWTN News uses security practices and technology that meets or exceeds Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI-DSS) and requires the same of the payment gateways that process your payment card or banking information.

**Our Commitment to Accuracy**

In addition to maintaining privacy and security controls for information you share with us, EWTN News uses error checking procedures to accurately and completely process your transaction information. Our staff is available Monday through Friday from 9am to 6pm (US Eastern Time) to answer questions by phone at 1-205-271-2989 or by email at [viewer@ewtn.com](mailto:viewer@ewtn.com).

Changes are made to our error checking procedures as necessary to improve our system and independent external audits are periodically conducted to ensure the appropriate processing of your information from our web site.

**Use of "Cookies"**

Visitors to the EWTN News web site should be aware that non-personal information and data is automatically collected by the EWTN News web site through the use of "cookies." "Cookies" are small text files which a web site can use to recognize repeat visitors, facilitate a visitor's ongoing access to, and use of, the site, and allow a web site to track usage behavior and compile data that will allow content improvements. If a visitor does not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows the visitor to deny or accept the cookie feature. EWTN News uses "cookie" technology only to obtain non-personal information from its online visitors in order to improve visitors' online experience and facilitate their visit of EWTN News's web site.

Video players and country selection are saved as an anonymous cookie that stores the region you selected when visiting this website.  We use this cookie to provide you with the video streams, programming guides, and other information relevant to your region.  We also use this cookie to determine if content is licensed for exhibition rights in your region.  Because we must, by license restrictions, control the territories in which some certain video content is exhibited, cookies are the best method for us to determine if content is available to your region without interrupting your use of the website and services.  The video player may not function correctly if it cannot determine the location from which it is being viewed.

**Use of Analytics Services – Information We Collect from Others**

EWTN News uses certain third party services to measure the usability and interest in our site, our applications, and content.  EWTN News uses the information from these services to determine whether our website services are delivered correctly and timely to visitors.  These services also help EWTN News to determine the interests of our audience and segments of our audience.  These services provide information to us about you and your use of our websites and applications.

Google Analytics.  EWTN News uses Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager to analyze site visitors and actions on the websites and in apps.  EWTN News does not provide any personal information to this service.  It provides anonymized and aggregated data about visitors, users, and actions they take on the site or in apps to EWTN News.  Their privacy policy is located [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

Facebook Analytics products:  Pixel, Connect, and Audience.  Facebook provides EWTN News with analytics regarding the interests of audience segments and information about our audiences, including demographic data, location, and similar.  Facebook does not provide your personal information to EWTN News.  Your privacy settings on Facebook may result in us being able to see information you allow us to see.  Their privacy policy is located [here](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php).

Brightcove.  Brightcove provides video delivery and player services for EWTN News video on the site.  Brightcove collects viewing data about videos.  EWTN News uses this data to determine the performance of EWTN News video distribution, audience interest in video topics, and other relevant metrics to continue to improve and provide programming through the website and apps.  Their privacy policy is located [here](https://www.brightcove.com/en/legal/privacy).

Hubspot.  Some EWTN News websites and services use Hubspot to assist with subscriber communications and measuring audience interest in articles and topics.  Hubspot manages email communications on behalf of EWTN News and provides a service though which EWTN News can match subscriber activity on the website with communications to and from the subscriber.  Hubspot provides this service for EWTN News but it may not use any information EWTN News stores in its account for any purpose other than to provide the service to EWTN News.  Hubspot’s Privacy Policy is located [here](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy).

**Retargeting Advertising**

We may use services that advertise to you because you visited a page or portion of our website or application or serves ads to you because you responded to an earlier ad (“remarketing”).  You will see these advertisements in places away from our websites and applications, but the advertisement is based on your prior visit here.  These services usually use cookies to determine if they will remarket an ad to you.  You can opt-out of this type of advertising with the advertising agencies:

To opt-out of Google Ads remarketing, visit the [Google Ads Settings page](http://www.google.com/settings/ads).

To opt-out of Facebook ads remarketing, visit the [Facebook Help Center](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217).

More information and a unified opt-out are available from the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

**Use of Advertising Networks to place ads on the Website**

Some websites and services of EWTN News may contain advertising that was placed from an advertising network.  Advertising networks use cookies and other information about your devices and you in order to serve advertising.  Each of these networks may use cookies and other automatically collected information to determine which advertisements they will show to you.  EWTN News provides no personal or other information to these services, and the information they collect comes from their interaction with the browser and device you use to access the website(s) or applications.    In addition to the remarketing advertising above, the following ad networks may place ads on this website, and a link to their policies follows each:

  * CleanMedia: [privacy policy](http://cleanmedia.net/company/PrivacyPolicy/).
  * Wibbitz:  [privacy policy](https://www.wibbitz.com/privacy-policy/)  .
  * Hadoq:  [privacy policy](https://hadoq.com/cookies).
  * Amazon: [privacy policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496).

**Information You Voluntarily Provide**

The websites and applications have places where you may choose to provide us with your personal information.  These include signing up for our email newsletters, making a donation, or using comments and message boards.  If you share your email and name with us in order to receive emails from us, we may use a service to manage the email on our behalf, but we will not give your personal information to others for them to email you.  If you contact us, we collect the information and contact details you provide to us.

**Information that is Automatically Collected**

Our servers and infrastructure used to deliver the Websites, content, and applications to you employ a number of industry standard practices, such as firewalls, and these devices automatically collect information about you and the devices you use to access the websites and application.  This information can include, your IP address, operating system, browser software, referring website, pages you viewed, and when the access occurred.  Events, such as clicking links, will also be collected.  This information is collected for a number of legitimate reasons.  Some of our infrastructure uses this information to determine security threats.  Some of our infrastructure uses this data to determine if the infrastructure is operating correctly and serving your visit without errors.  Some of this data is used for us to determine the performance of our infrastructure. 

**Publicly Visible Information:   Message Boards and Public Forums**

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information on our web site (for example, on message boards such as the Catholic Q&A and Bulletin Board) that information may be viewed on the website by the public and other visitors to the websites or applications.  That means that it could be collected and used by others.

**Links to Other Sites**

This web site may contain links to other web sites. Please be aware that EWTN News is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other web sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our web site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information from you. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by the EWTN News web site.

**Opt-out**

If you no longer wish to receive electronic mailings from us, you may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the "unsubscribe" information contained at the bottom of the message or by contacting us as indicated below.

**Contact our Web Site**

Thank you for visiting our web site. We are available to answer your questions and hear your concerns. For inquiries concerning our information practices and Privacy Policy, you may contact us at:

EWTN News, Inc.  
Attention: Jeffrey Hahn  
5817 Old Leeds Rd.  
Irondale, AL 35210-2164

or e-mail us at [viewer@ewtn.com](mailto:viewer@ewtn.com)

**Shared Marketing Models – Transactions and Postal Mail**

We will sometimes share information gathered from our audience with select third party vendors who assist us with promoting and marketing our news content. This might include customer database modeling, or use of information to identify other individuals similar to our audience for external promotional mailings or other online marketing. This information may include your name, address, e-mail address and transaction history.

  The National Catholic Register occasionally shares subscriber data including name, address and purchase method, amount, channel, and date with marketing partners.  We do not share email addresses or credit card information.  If you do not want your information shared, you can opt out of that at any time.  One request for opting out will ensure that your data is not shared with any marketing partner.

  **To Opt Out of Shared Marketing Model Use**

You may request, at any time, that we do not share your information with these third parties. Please contact RegisterMarketing@ewtn.com or call 800-356-9916 if you do not wish for your information to be shared in this manner.

In an effort to provide the best service, EWTN News reserves the right to edit, modify, and improve this policy at any time.

Rev. October 8, 2018
